Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth, upon this
continent, a new nation, conceived in liberty, and dedicated to the
proposition that all men are created equal. Now we are engaged in a
great civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation, so
conceived, and so dedicated, can long endure. We are met here on a
great battlefield of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of
it as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that
that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we
should do this. But in a larger sense we can not dedicate - we can not
consecrate - we can not hallow this ground. The brave men, living and
dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it far above our poor power
to add or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember, what
we say here, but can never forget what they did here. It is for us, the
living, rather to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they
have, thus far, so nobly carried on. It is rather for us to be here
dedicated to the great task remaining before us that from these honored
dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they here gave
the last full measure of devotion - that we here highly resolve that
these dead shall not have died in vain; that this nation shall have a
new birth of freedom; and that this government of the people, by the
people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth.